What is this craziness? I had no idea about this at all.
My last challenge, where I blindly recode a somewhat complicated button,
has piqued the interest of the French dev community.
A bunch of subscribers took on the challenge.
The adorable Liorchamla made his attempt on his side.
As well as Graphicart, the great Graphicart, who tried his hand on his Twitch channel.
Among the subscribers, one of them taught me a completely improbable CSS trick,
a craziness that I had no idea about at all,
and which is going to greatly revolutionize my way of approaching a particular case.
Today, we're going to take a little tour of everyone's results,
and we're going to see this crazy trick that at least 99% of you definitely don't know.
I'm convinced of that.
So, let's take a little tour of the results of the work that was submitted to me.
You'll see that everyone got quite different results.
That's normal, at the same time, they all code blindly like this,
and at one point, boom, they look at the result.
That's what we're going to see right away, it's the moment they looked at the result.
So, Liorch, who isn't really a front-end developer,
on the contrary, he's a guy who teaches PHP online,
Symfony, Laravel, and a bunch of other things.
Honestly, if you don't know this guy, go check out his YouTube channel.
He's a great guy with a charmingly cute Marseille accent.
And so, here's his proposal.
It's a big challenge for him to take on this realization,
because he's not necessarily used to doing this kind of integration.
He's missing a bit of the font, but that's okay.
The effect is quite good, Liorch.
And on top of that, you decided to do this animation in SVG,
which isn't easy when you're doing it blindly.
Honestly, well done, Liorch.
The vertical alignment isn't great, you can see it's not really centered in the middle of the block.
Here, it also lacks a bit of padding on this side,
it would have been nice to have about the same space you have there and here.
And then, well, the font is missing, but for the rest, you have almost everything.
So honestly, it's not bad. Respect, my dear friend.
Next, we have GraphicCart.
So GraphicCart also took the SVG approach,
and he presented it to us in two ways.
So this is the rendering he got when he discovered it blindly,
and this is the rendering when he corrected it afterwards.
So, what does the blind rendering look like?
Hey, it's not bad at all.
There's the underline there that's a bit too much, okay.
But otherwise, the paddings on each side are well respected,
and he has the arrow that is a little off.
But then, I heard about his live stream,
and I was told he coded the SVG blindly.
Look, crazy stuff.
Like if we go here, this stuff here, he wrote it blindly,
he calculated it in his head.
This big, big, big crazy guy.
Who today is capable of doing something like that?
In any case, GraphicCart, respect for doing something like that blindly,
it's impressive.
Your finished version is here.
It's flawless, super stylish, well done.
Honestly, GraphicCart, you took on something a bit complicated blindly,
and you nailed it.
So, that's totally respectable.
The discovered version, and the corrected version.
Well done to you.
Next, we have Hélène.
So, Hélène, I've already talked about her in a video.
She's the really cool guy who, as soon as I release a challenge,
within the next hour, has redone the challenge on her side,
and posts it on Twitter.
Honestly, it's not bad.
It's not bad at all for something done blindly.
GG, you have the arrow that is a little off.
But everything else is top-notch.
So, well done to you, it's validated.
Next, we have Mario.
A bit complex to say.
Who also did the challenge.
I also did the challenge to practice,
but ah, not blindfolded.
Unfortunately, I don't have the level yet.
So, let's see what you did.
There, you should have added a bit more weight to that.
But after that, it's still not bad.
Well done to you.
Next, what do we have?
We have Valentin R.
Where, Valentin?
Ah, you messed up a bit.
But Valentin, I love it.
He's a young apprentice.
He's brand new to the game,
and he's super eager to learn.
He learns all the things.
He does all the challenges.
So, a big GG to you,
even if it's a bit rough.
It's normal, you had your eyes blindfolded.
And it's a super complicated test when you're blindfolded.
So, there you go, it is what it is.
But now, try to correct it by unblindfolding yourself.
That's the right way to go.
So, on my side, here's this little G.
So, let's see.
Oh dear, Michel, you kind of messed with me on the bar.
Three little lines.
Well.
There's some trickery in the air.
It's not very convincing, in the end.
But well, if you're blindfolded, you can't criticize too much.
So, that's it for the few results I got.
Once again, I remind you,
it's people like that,
they did the challenge blindly,
and finally, they looked at the result all at once,
and they sent me exactly the result at that moment.
So, for the most part, it was still not bad at all,
or rather very well done.
Well, there are a few accidents, but that's normal.
Nothing serious.
Well, and now, the crazy trick I learned,
thanks to a subscriber.
Remember, my result was exactly that.
Oh my God, it was terrible.
I had this arrow that was going down,
and I was depressed.
My arrow, if it goes down,
it's because I did it all in CSS,
and actually, at the base, my arrow is just a square,
that is like this, that is straight,
with a top border and a right border, like this.
I rotate it to simulate the tip of an arrow.
So there you go, we rotate the thing.
And the thing is that afterwards, on hover, basically,
so if we display the hover,
it's on the button that I'm going to put the hover.
We see that our arrow is still rotated,
to keep the arrow look, you know.
And then, we translate it like this, to the right.
For me, to solve this, actually, in the test,
I removed the translate here,
there, basically,
and I applied it on top.
I applied it here, basically.
Transform, Translate, 30 pixels.
And I also removed it from the body.
I had solved the thing like that.
Rather than applying the translate on the tip of the arrow,
and the body of the arrow,
I had applied it on the parent.
I had applied it on the whole, which moved like this, actually.
But I could have kept my solution as I created it,
by doing something much simpler.
I reinforce the hover.
And actually, here, friends,
if, instead of doing Rotate 45° and Translate 3D,
I had first done Translate 3D and then Rotate,
there, you saw, it's good.
What is this craziness?
I had no idea about this at all,
but actually, what we learn here, what we view together,
is that the order in transforms is important.
If you first do a Rotate and then Translate on the X-axis,
the X-axis will be like this, down.
On the other hand, if you first do a Translate,
and then you do a Rotate, it will happen like this.
This thing is completely mind-blowing,
that the order in Translate was important, I didn't know that,
and I think very few front-end developers know it, anyway.
Let me know in the comments if you knew this trick or not.
I would like us to organize a sort of little poll in the comments
to see if there were really a lot of devs who knew it
or a lot of devs who completely ignored it.
Because for me, clearly, I think no one knows this thing.
Or not many people, anyway.
Earlier, I ran into Bastille at Micode and I asked him
if he would be up for the next challenge we do on the channel,
and well, it's him who designs it for me.
And we're going to do a sort of little collab like that.
By the way, look at what he told me.
Bastille?
Yeah?
Are you up for making me the next challenge
that I'm going to do blindfolded coding in the dark?
I’ve been waiting for this for years, of course.
Yes!
Ah!
That's what I wanted to hear.
Oh yes!
It's going to be...
But you promise me you're going to make me something simple?
No.
So the next challenge on this channel will be in two weeks.
If you don't want to miss it, subscribe.
And that's it!
I'll see you soon, everyone.
This was Benjamin Code.
Ciao!