How much money do you make?
Make $1 million every month.
How old are you?
I'm 17.
Okay. What do you do? What is it?
I build mobile consumer apps. Specifically, this one is CalAI.
Okay.
So today we will be editing a podcast style reel. So let's begin. First of all,
what you can see over here is the whole, you know, tone of the video is bouncy animations.
So we need to remember that whatever animations we use, be it text or image,
we need to make it a bit bouncy. I have got the raw video over here.
Everything will be there in the description. So you'll be able to practice along.
Now, as you can see over here in the start, how much money do you make?
Okay. This text is here. So what we need to do is first bring in a default text and write the text.
Then I'll bring this.
Make it smaller like this and put it over here. Let me zoom this in for better visibility.
Bring this money bag and put it inside this.
Simply need to make this bigger and hit Alt plus G for a compound clip.
Then this, do you make?
I'll head on to stickers, select shapes, bring this line over here and increase the weight.
Head on to cap and click around to get this shape.
To get the shape.
Let's decrease the scaling to make it smaller and let's make this blue.
Copy this and place this over here. Rotate this and finally bring this square.
Increase the width, decrease the height. Zoom this in again.
Put this behind the text of do you make?
Select this same color, but you have to decrease the opacity.
Okay. So we have created this. As you can see over here, there are two boxes, but we'll make that.
So first let's do the animation. How much money do you make?
So I'm going to make this blue and then I'm going to increase the height to make it smaller.
How much money do you make?
So in the first part, he's saying, how much money do you make?
So I have to cut everything till here because this is where it ends.
In the starting of the video, I advised you to do all the animations in a bouncy manner.
So for the text animations, these are some of the bouncy text animations, which I found.
Okay. Not this like wiggle landing, ocean bounce, leap in, wave bounce, wave in.
Okay. You can use whichever you want. So how much money?
I'm randomly choosing them because everything is bouncy animation.
How much money?
Okay. And after that, let's do this animation. So this animation to make it bouncy,
what we have to do first is now go 15 frames ahead and again, click on the transform keyframe.
Now at the first keyframe, just drag this down a bit like this.
And the second keyframe, overshoot it, meaning drag this up from the original or the finished
position, just a bit more up. Then go 10 frames ahead and I'll bring this down now. Okay.
This is the finished position, but a bit below that. Then I'll go eight frames ahead
and this time again, drag this up a little bit and then go a bit down.
Then after three frames, just finish the animation at the fixed position. So as you can see,
it is going up, then down, then up and down and up. And finally it is stable at the final position.
Okay. So as you can see, first I have used the gap of 15 frames, then 10 frames, eight, five,
three. Okay. This is because with each bounce, the height becomes smaller. This is a simple
animation rule of DK. Okay. So with each bounce, the height becomes smaller. You can also see this
in a ball. So when you drop the ball, after first bounce, it will go to a certain height. Then when
the second bounce is there, it will bounce a little bit lower than the first. And then with the third
bounce, a little bit lower than the second and like that. Now hit Alt plus K. And as you can see,
this is the graph in the Y coordinate. Select them and make them auto curve like this.
So you can see. This is the animation, but it's too slow. Okay.
So what we have to do is basically head on to speed and increase the speed like this.
So now just head on to blend keyframe. Go ahead. Again, click on the blend keyframe.
And at the starting, make this opacity zero. Now hit Alt plus K and open this blend and make
this cubic out. Now simply just copy this, hit Alt plus G to compound clip it
again and drag this up like this. Offset this a bit. Simply select the shape. Okay.
And simply select bounce in. So you will get the bounce animation.
And for this one.
How much money? Again, bounce in. How much money do you make? And as you can see in the starting.
How much money do you make? So what we can also do is head on to effects, search for blur.
And add blur on top of everything. Head on to mask, add mask.
And make this selection and reverse it. Add feathering. Okay. To get that edge blur.
And again, just search for vignette. Bring this over here. And also I'll add,
head on to filters and add glow effect over here. Simply select everything and hit B to
cut it. Okay.
Except these three. Let's extend these and now as you can see over here make
and then so this number counting animation I
Provided this animation you can directly use this
Okay, because in CapCut it will take too much time to create this manually. So I've given you the
Animation make 1 million dollars every month. How
How much money do you make make 1 million dollars?
And then simply I'll just
Copy put this text over here type here mate
Put it over here
head on to animation
Select we will make one
It make 1 million dollars and these bounce animations. Okay now
remember this
Compound clip which you made copy this over here
Head on inside and I'll increase this
Again, head on inside delete these and bring the stripe message over here now head back on out
Now you can see the bounce animation has been replicated. Let's increase this
Make 1 million
Put this over here
Copy this and again
Copy this
Second one put it below
The third one at the last
As you can see these are coming together, which we don't want. So first we want the top one, okay
Which is this then offset the second one and the third one like this make 1 million dollars every month
Let's see the first two animations. How much money do you make make 1 million dollars every month Howard?
now for this animation
So this is the message pop-up animation again will use the same method which we used in the stripe messages
so basically just
Copy them over here
The first message will be how old are you? So just head on inside this
Okay, delete this and bring this message head back on out
How are you
Simply just bring this over here
Make this smaller
How are you sir?
So when this comes
You simply select these two, okay
Transform keyframe on both of them
Go ahead
Like this and again a transform keyframe select both of them and drag them up
Select all plus K
Give it out, okay
Okay
For you, I'm 17. Okay. What do you and for the last animation also, so what do you do?
Select these all okay, so
Somewhere around here
To select the transform keyframe on all of these three. Okay, not the last one only these three then go ahead
Select all of these and drag them up hit R plus K
You do what
You do what are you 17, okay, what do you do? What is it?
I how much money do you make make 1 million dollars every month. How old are you? I'm 17
Okay, what do you do? What is it? I build
Now for this part of the animation, so this will be interesting. This is a full-scale animation
What we have to do here is simply first head on to stickers. Bring this in
And
Use it for the whole duration make this 600 to cover the whole screen and now just make the color
white
Also, we need to
Delete all these three. Okay, because this is a full-screen animation. Okay, you don't need blur and those all things
Okay, maybe I think let's keep the blur
So
This image is there the circle is there. So what we need to do is
first bring this image
Make it smaller at the center
Now mask add mask make the circle
Select this. I'll decrease the opacity. So you'll be able to make circle properly
Okay, after making the circle we need to head on to stickers and in shapes. I'll bring this circle again and
simply delete the fill make the stroke and
And
Make sure that it fits the
Boundary of this image increase the weight of the stroke and make the color black and again bring another circle
Scale this up
Okay, decrease the opacity
Make sure the color is blue. Okay, and also include a stroke
Let me see the reference
So, yeah, the stroke is also blue, okay make this blue
Decrease the weight to
two and
Finally make another circle first this image circle then this one. Okay
Gray circle or black and then this blue one. So one two and three now just
after copying this
Simply delete the fill
Make the stroke to black
okay, so you get this and
Increase this weight increase the scale
Now we need to attach these images in the outer circle and then bring this image
Put it over here, let me just head on back to our background and increase back the opacity
You
Okay now after attaching these simply just select these all
Images and the last circle hit or press G to make a compound clip
Now if you rotate them, you can see it is rotating somewhere from around here
First as you can see you have to bounce this in okay like this
Select these two images hit or plus G
Okay to get this click on the
scale
Go ahead and again scale now go to the start now again
We have to do the same thing, but this time by using only scale go ahead 15 frames
Bring the keyframe over here, okay and
Increase the scale a bit then go ahead 10 frames
You
Decrease the scale.
Okay, go below 100% Okay, at the first you can see it is 100 Sorry, it should be zero,
but I'll tell you and the second it should be above 100 in the third it should be below
100 Okay, at the start it has to be zero zero Okay, so it will come up then down and then
again go seven frames ahead increase the scale go five frames ahead, make this 95 and three
frames ahead and make it perfect 100 Okay, so you get this, you can see this bouncing
effect and now simply add plus k do the same thing which we did earlier.
Select this or took off everything I build mobile consumer on plus k and then speed increase
it to 2x I build mobile cons I build mobile and the same thing you have to do for this
large circle which is this one Okay, so simply just copy this over here Okay, head back inside
copy all this Okay, open this compound clipping delete this and paste it over here.
So you can see the same animation and now I'll delete this compound clip as you can
see but this is looking like one animation so I build mobile consumer app so for this
one what I have done is I have used only four keyframes and for this so the last two bounces
I have deleted the keyframes Okay, I have used only four bounces so so the speed is
different this is 1.5x and this is two and as you can see this comes in Okay, so this
one this is an easy effect what you have to do is basically after this goes up simply
just scale this up till here Okay, then click on the scale keyframe go ahead again click
on the scale keyframe go to this starting keyframe make the zero hit R plus K and select
you become a consumer or consumer shrink this down Okay animation out and fade out
sumer app do more apps or consumer app and just simply hit alt and drag with your mouse
button to copy Okay, and again when this ends over here just copy it again put it here specifically
the consumer apps specifically this one put it over here Okay below this so now we need
to do the rotation animation or this so it opens up bounces mobile like the rotation
keyframe go ahead and just rotate this at a fast pace Okay hit R plus K give it out
mobile consumer apps specifically this one so this last animation is for you to do you
have to bring a PNG of a mouse button and bring this over here like this Okay so let's
see the animation what we have created how much money do you make make 1 million dollars
every month how old are you 17 Okay what do you do what is it I build mobile consumer
apps specifically this one is Okay hope you like this podcast editing tutorial if you
would like me to create more podcast editing style videos in CapCut let me know in the
comments below till then see you in the next video.